▍2026 美网 女单16强
郑钦文 7-5 6-3 斯瓦泰克 · 赛后场上采访
Qinwen, congratulations.
钦文 恭喜你
What an unbelievable performance
刚刚那场表现
that was.
太不可思议了
But I have to ask in the previous round
但我必须问一下 上一轮
against Madison Keys,
对阵凯斯那场
you were down five zero in the third set.
你决胜盘 0-5 落后
Here again in the first set,
今天第一盘又是这样
how are you making these comebacks?
你是怎么完成这些逆转的？
Well, honestly,
说实话
I have to say I start the match not so well
我得说 开场我打得不太好
and after, little by little, I find
然后我一点一点
my rhythm on the center court cuz it's
找回了中央球场的节奏
been a long long time I haven't play
因为已经很久很久
on the center court,
我没在中央球场打过了
I just really appreciate it to be here
我真的很珍惜能站在这里
in the Ashe Stadium first.
站在阿什球场
Yeah.
是的
And second, I just focus point by point
第二 我就是一分一分地打
and little by little I start
然后一点一点
to play better tennis.
打出更好的网球
I start to find my game
我开始找回自己的球
and in one moment I even forgot the score
有一刻我甚至忘了比分
in the first set at 4-5.
就在第一盘 4-5 的时候
That shows how I am focused.
这说明我有多专注
Well I guess to come back 0-5 yesterday
昨天从 0-5 追回来
is not lucky.
不是靠运气
That's all I can say.
我只能说这么多
It's been a very difficult head-to-head
你和斯瓦泰克的交手
with Iga.
一直非常艰难
She's won six out of six matches.
六次交手她赢了六次
What did you do differently today?
今天你做了什么不一样的？
Well,
嗯
I think in the baseline I try to play more flat
底线上我试着打得更平
against her because I think she's
因为她的上旋球
has really good top spin.
质量真的很高
Makes me feel really uncomfortable
让我很不舒服
and I try to play more aggressive
所以我打得更主动
because I remember when I just came
因为我记得刚打巡回赛时
on the tour the match I lost against her
输给她的那些场
is because I wasn't aggressive enough
就是因为我不够主动
and I tried to stay with her as long as I can.
只想着尽量跟她周旋
I'm just really happy to match
我真的很高兴赢下这场
because it's not easy
因为这不容易
and it's been a while really.
而且真的隔了很久
I didn't beat any top 10 player.
我一直没赢过前 10 的球员
I just really really appreciated this win
我真的非常珍惜
for me.
这场胜利
And I want to say thank you for all the fans
我想谢谢所有的球迷
who come to support me today.
今天来现场支持我
And I hope you guys enjoy tennis.
希望你们享受这场网球
And last thing I want
最后我想
to say thanks to my team
谢谢我的团队
because we've been working really hard.
我们一直非常努力
That's why I'm here.
所以我才能站在这里
Qinwen, you were out with injury
钦文 你因伤缺席了
for quite some time.
相当长一段时间
You made it through the qualifying here,
你从这里的资格赛打上来
but now you're into the quarterfinals.
现在已经打进 8 强
You're playing some
你打出的是
of the best tennis we've ever seen from you.
我们见过你最好的网球
Are you ready to keep going?
你准备好继续走下去了吗？
Well, I have to say more matches I play,
我得说 打的比赛越多
more rhythm I got on court.
场上的节奏就越好
People often ask me if you are tired.
常有人问我累不累
I mean, when I arrive to here,
我到这儿的时候
I'm not tired at all.
一点都不累
I just feel really pumped for my next match.
我对下一场充满干劲
Trying to reach better level here.
想在这里打到更高的水平
Trying to show my tennis
想展示我的网球
and enjoy at this fantastic stadium.
享受这座了不起的球场
Congratulations.
恭喜你